Working in Paterson Project Collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series I: Manuscript Materials
  - (Box 3)
      - Watson Machinery International (Folder 70)
        Brochure, correspondence, photo, miscellaneous information. 4 pages.
    - Forms
      - Biographical Data Forms (Folder 71)
        Completed forms. 97 pages.
      - Informant Consent and Data Forms, Masters (Folder 72)
        Master copies. 3 pages.
      - Informant Consent Forms (Folder 73)
        Completed forms. 115 pages.
    - Disk Directories
      - Disk Directories (Folder 74)
        Logs describing data to be found on diskettes (now found on zip disk); arranged alphabetically by fieldworkers' surname. 12 pages.
    - Audio Tape Logs
      - CARROLL, Tom (2 folders) (Folder 75-76)
        WIP-TDC-A001 through WIP-TDC-A027. 179 pages.
      - LEVITAS, Susan (Folder 77)
        WIP-SL-A001 through WIP-SL-A022. 94 pages.
  - (Box 4)
      - LLOYD, Timothy (Folder 78)
        WIP-TL-A001 through WIP-TL-A002. 7 pages.
      - McCARL, Robert (Folder 79)
        WIP-RM-A001 through WIP-RM-A011. 53 pages.
      - TAYLOR, David (Folder 80)
        WIP-DT-A003, A004, A008-A011, A018, A019, A022-26. 26 pages.
    - Black and White Photo Logs
      - CARROLL, Tom (Folder 81)
        WIP-TDC-B001 through WIP-TDC-B012. 30 pages.
      - COOPER, Martha (Folder 82)
        WIP-MC-B001 through WIP-MC-B016. 17 pages.
      - LEVITAS, Susan (Folder 83)
        WIP-SL-B001 through WIP-SL-B010. 14 pages.
      - LLOYD, Timothy (Folder 84)
        WIP-TL-B001. 2 pages.
      - McCARL, Robert (Folder 85)
        WIP-RM-B001 through WIP-RM-B015. 15 pages.
      - TAYLOR, David (Folder 86)
        WIP-DT-B001 through WIP-DT-B004. 4 pages.
    - Color Photo Logs
      - CARROLL, Tom (Folder 87)
        WIP-TDC-C001 through WIP-TDC-C027. 48 pages.
      - COOPER, Martha (Folder 88)
        WIP-MC-C001- through WIP-MC-C097. 98 pages.
      - LEVITAS, Susan (Folder 89)
        WIP-SL-C001 through WIP-SL-C015. 16 pages.
      - LLOYD, Timothy (Folder 90)
        WIP-TL-C001 through WIP-TL-C003. 3 pages.
      - McCARL, Robert (Folder 91)
        WIP-RM-C001 through WIP-RM-C027. 26 pages.
      - TAYLOR, David (Folder 92)
        WIP-DT-C001 through WIP-DT-C008. 8 pages.
    - Fieldnotes
      - CARROLL, Tom (Folder 93)
        WIP-TDC-F061894 through WIP-TDC-F090994. 284 pages.
      - LEVITAS, Susan (Folder 94)
        WIP-SL-F080394.A through WIP-SL-F082994.A. 75 pages.
      - LLOYD, Timothy (Folder 95)
        WIP-TL-F081794 through WIP-TL-F081894. 3 pages.
      - McCARL, Robert (Folder 96)
        WIP-RM-F080294 through WIP-RM-F081794. 55 pages.
      - TAYLOR, David (Folder 97)
        WIP-DT-F080494 through WIP-DT-F081194. 13 pages.
    - Unpublished Reports and Products
      - CARROLL, Tom (Folder 98)
        "21st Avenue Report." January 3, 1995 (Revised on October 2, 1995). Essay explaining the rationale for conducting the study of the 21st Avenue commercial area in Paterson, New Jersey. 35 pages.
      - Correspondence regarding reports (Folder 99)
        Paterson reports. July 1996. 5 pages.
  - (Box 5)
      - Final Report (Folder 100)
        "Working in Paterson: A Survey of Occupational Culture in Paterson, New Jersey, with Recommendations for Public Programming" edited by David A. Taylor. Bound, with color photos. 1997. 169 pages.
      - LEVITAS, Susan (Folder 101)
        "Working in Paterson: African American Experiences, a Report on Fieldwork Conducted for the American Folklife Center." January 1995. 39 pages.
      - LLOYD, Timothy (Folder 102)
        "Work and Food: Paterson's Hot Texas Wiener Tradition." No date. (2 copies) 44 pages.
      - McCARL, Robert (Folder 103)
        "Working in Paterson: Watson Machine International." No date. (2 copies) 27 pages.
      - "Notes From Field-Perspectives on the Collections and Work of the American Folklife Center" (Folder 104)
        Announcement for "Working in Paterson: Documenting Occupational Heritage in Paterson, New Jersey," lecture given by David A. Taylor. August 28, 1996. 4 copies.
      - Report Draft (Folder 105)
        "Working in Paterson: A Survey of Occupational Culture in Paterson, New Jersey, with Recommendations for Public Programming," edited by David A. Taylor. Report submitted to the Mid-Atlantic Regional Office of the National Park Service, and the Paterson Urban History Initiative Advisory Committee, by the American Folklife Center. Report draft. 1995. 173 pages.
      - Report Outline (Folder 106)
        "Working in Paterson: A Survey of Occupational Culture in Paterson, New Jersey, with Recommendations for Public Programming," edited by David A. Taylor. Report submitted to the Mid-Atlantic Regional Office of the National Park Service and The Paterson Urban History Initiative Advisory Committee, by the American Folklife Center. Report outline. 1994. 8 pages.
      - Selected Documentation (Folder 107)
        Audio tape logs, black-and-white photo logs, color slide logs, fieldnotes. "Working in Paterson Project: A Study of Occupational Heritage in Paterson, New Jersey 1994." 86 pages.
      - Slide Show Lectures (Folder 108)
        Notes from David Taylor's slide-show lecture on the Working In Paterson Project Collection. No date. 24 pages.
      - TAYLOR, David (Folder 109)
        "Narratives of Work: Stories Told by Retired Workers and Their Children." No date. 21 pages.
    - Publications (Post-Fieldwork)
      - As I Was Saying..., April 14-May 17, 1996 (Folder 110)
        Booklet from The Paterson Museum Exhibit, 'As I Was Saying...' Reflections of African Americans in Paterson. Many of the same informants had also contributed to the Working in Paterson project.
      - Cianci Street: A Neighborhood In Transition (Folder 111)
        By June Avignone, Photographs by Ellen Denuto. Paterson, New Jersey: Italian Girls Press, 1996.
      - Downtown Paterson (Folder 112)
        Edited by June Avignone. Charleston, South Carolina: Arcadia Publishing, 1999: Includes an essay by Tom Carroll.
      - Mary Ellen Newsletters (Folder 113)
        Newsletter of the Alexander Hamilton National Memorial. January 2001, March 2001, April 2001, June 2001, and July 2001. 6 newsletters.
      - Articles (Folder 114)
        Allee, Rod, "A step at last to dignify the Great Falls," The Record, March 14, 2001.
        Austin, Charles, "A Bit of Paterson's Past Glory Debuts at the Library of Congress," NorthJersey.com, 2002.
        Boehlert, Eric; Hansen, Suzy; and Stark, Jeff, "Our fight is for Jerusalem, not New York," Salon.com News, 2001.
        Casey, Michael, "Downtown dilemma," The Record, March 8, 2001.
        Cichowski, John, "Hamilton honored at Great Falls gathering," The Record, February 20, 2001.
        "Lautenberg Library Unveiled at Labor Museum," Italian Voice, Vol. 69, No. 19, p. 6, October 5, 2000.
        Llorente, Elizabeth, "Painting A New Portrait of New Jersey," The Record, October 24, 1999.
        "Many Faces, One Family: Portraits of Our City," Fall 1996.
        "New Online: Working in Paterson," The Gazette, May 10, 2002.
        Pfaff, Leslie Garisto, "Silk City Saga," New Jersey Monthly, December 2001.
        Vekshin, Alison, "Paterson national park bid on hold," The Record, March 14, 2001.
        Vekshin, Alison,"House Oks Great Falls park study," State News Service, May 10, 2001.
      - Paterson Museum Coloring Book (Folder 115)
        The Story of Paterson coloring book. 20 pages.
      - Paterson Museum Pamphlets (Folder 116)
        The History of Paterson's Silk Industry 1839-1945
        The Story of Wright Aeronautics
        John Philip Holland 1841-1914
        A Brief History of The Society for Establishing Useful Manufactures
        Thomas Rogers Building
        A Brief History of the Great Falls; 6 pamphlets.
  - (Box 6)
      - Squeaky Chalk and Other Fun Things To Draw (and do) When There is Nothing To Do! (Folder 117)
        By Joy Sikorski. New York: Crown Publishers, 2000. The author is from Paterson and her work appears in the Mary Ellen newsletters.
    - Online Presentation
      - AFCWIP Batch 1-35mm black-and-white negatives (Folder 118)
        CD-ROM inventory sheets. 100 pages.
      - AFCWIP Batch 2-Color slides (3 folders) (Folder 119-121)
        CD-ROM inventory sheets. 300 pages.
      - Audio conversion procedures (Folder 122)
        Information on digitizing sound recordings. 13 pages.
      - CARROLL, Tom (Folder 123)
        Carroll's selection, from his audio logs, of possible online excerpts. 181 pages.
      - Cataloging (Folder 124)
        Subject terms for cataloging Working in Paterson photographs (I and II); notes from cataloging meetings; list of events and themes from the Working in Paterson collection. 59 pages.
      - Copyright Permission Request (Folder 125)
        Copyright permission correspondence for Paterson postcard used in online presentation. 11 pages.
  - (Box 7)
      - Correspondence (Folder 126)
        Correspondence announcing the Working in Paterson online presentation project. 11 pages.
      - Framework (Folder 127)
        Drafts and edited versions of text for Working in Paterson online presentation; correspondence regarding framework; notes from design meeting. 36 pages.
      - LEVITAS, Susan (Folder 128)
        "WIP Audio Tape Inventory" for audio collection; fields include: tape number, fieldworker, informant, recording date, subject matter, recording format, recording length. Selections, from her audio logs, of possible online excerpts. 94 pages.
      - McCARL, Robert (Folder 129)
        "WIP Audio Tape Inventory" for audio collection. 51 pages.
      - Announcement about online presentation (Folder 130)
        3 pages.
      - Permission Forms, First Request (Irradiated Originals) (Folder 131)
        Due to the fragility of the irradiated originals, please refer to the photocopies.
      - Permission Forms, Second Request (Irradiated Originals) (Folder 132)
      - Permission Forms Received (Irradiated Originals) (A-L) (Folder 133)
      - Permission Forms Received (Irradiated Originals) (M-Sch) (Folder 134)
  - (Box 8)
      - Permission Forms Received (Irradiated Originals) (Se-Z) (Folder 135)
      - Permission Forms, First Request (Photocopies) (Folder 136)
      - Permission Forms, Second Request (Photocopies) (Folder 137)
      - Permission Forms Received (Photocopies) (A-L) (Folder 138)
      - Permission Forms Received (Photocopies) (M-S) (Folder 139)
      - Permission Forms Received (Photocopies) (T-Z) (Folder 140)
  - (Box 9)
      - Plan for Digital Collections, 1996-2000 (Folder 141)
        Correspondence, proposals, budget. 16 pages.
      - Planning (Folder 142)
        Outline, status reports, task lists, ephemera, meeting notes, planning template, questions and answers, budget. 38 pages.
      - TAYLOR, David (Folder 143)
        Table - "WIP Audio Tape Inventory" for Taylor's audio collection, fields include: tape number, fieldworker, informant, recording date, subject matter, recording format, recording length. Taylor's selections, from his audio logs, of possible online excerpts. 87 pages.
- Series II: Sound Recordings
  Note: Sound recordings originally housed in boxes are stored in a separate location. Duplicate copies, preservation copies, and reference copies of the original sound recordings are available on audiocassette tapes. Please contact Folklife Reading Room reference staff for descriptive lists of these copies.
  - Audiocassettes, Originals
    LLOYD, Timothy: WIP-TL-A001 through WIP-TL-A002
    McCARL, Robert: WIP-RM-A001 through WIP-RM-A011
    TAYLOR, David: WIP-DT-A001 through WIP-DT-A028
  - Digital Audio Tapes
    CARROLL, Tom: WIP-TDC-A001 through WIP-TDC-A027
    LEVITAS, Susan: WIP-SL-A001 through WIP-SL-A022
- Series III: Graphic Materials
  - Black-and-White Negatives
    - (Box 15)
      CARROLL, Tom: WIP-TDC-B001 through WIP-TDC-B012
      COOPER, Martha: WIP-MC-B001 through WIP-MC-B036
      LEVITAS, Susan: WIP-SL-B001 through WIP-SL-B010
      LLOYD, Timothy: WIP-TL-B001
      McCARL, Robert: WIP-RM-B001 through WIP-RM-B014
      TAYLOR, David: WIP-DT-B001 through WIP-DT-B004
  - Black-and-White Negatives Contact Sheet Binders
    - (Binder 1)
    - (Binder 2)
  - Color Slides
    - (Box 16-17)
      CARROLL, Tom: WIP-TC-C001 through WIP-TC-C025
    - (Box 18-26)
      COOPER, Martha: WIP-MC-C001 through WIP-MC-C114
    - (Box 26-27)
      LEVITAS, Susan: WIP-SL-C001 through WIP-SL-C015
    - (Box 28)
      LLOYD, Timothy: WIP-TL-C001 through WIP-TL-C003
    - (Box 28-30)
      McCARL, Robert: WIP-RM-C001 through WIP-RM-C027
    - (Box 30)
      TAYLOR, David: WIP-DT-C001 through WIP-DT-C008
  - Additional Graphic Material
    - (Box 38)
      Duplicate Slides [Folders 1 through 3] and Selected color photocopies of photographic prints and black-and-white photographs by COOPER, Martha.
- Series IV: Electronic Media
  - Administrative
    - (Box 1)
      - Zip Disk (Folder 1)
        Graphic Materials Database (Access): Fields include: ID number, frame, format, photographer, title, created/published, event, people in photo, location, notes, and repository.
        Sound Recordings Database (Access): Fields include: audio number, audio log, informant, date, location, event, subject, format/quantity, and length. 23 pages.
        Contents of Working in Paterson Project Collection diskettes:
        CARROLL, Tom: fieldnotes, final report, black and white photo logs, color photo logs, audio logs.
        COOPER, Martha: color photo logs
        LEVITAS, Susan: Fieldnotes, black and white photo logs, color photo logs, audio logs, final report
        McCARL, Robert: (Information is unavailable. See hard copies.)
        TAYLOR, David: fieldnotes, final report, black and white photo logs, color photo logs, audio logs (Information is not complete. See hard copies.)
        Working in Paterson Report
        Working in Paterson Group Level Database (Access).
  - CD-ROMs
    - JJT Image Deliverables, Batch 1 (Box 31)
      AFCWIP001 through AFCWIP019, AFCWIP033
    - JJT Image Deliverables, Batch 2 (Box 32-37)
      AFCWIP020 through AFCWIP177
    - Diskettes (Box 38)
      29 diskettes containing researchers' fieldwork, photo logs, slide logs, audio logs, and final report.
- Series V: Artifacts and Ephemera
  - Oversize
    - (Box 39)
      - The Mill Street Forward, June 1987, Vol. 1, No. 1. (Folder 51a)
      - The Mill Street Forward, Spring/Summer 1990, Vol. 1, No. 5. (Folder 51b)
      - A Keepsake of Memories. A booklet honoring the 125th anniversary of St. Joseph's Hospital and Medical Center. (Folder 144)
      - Building Our Tradition of Excellence. 125th anniversary commemorative booklet; a keepsake of memories- a history of St. Joseph's. (Folder 145)
      - Hand-held fan, courtesy of Carnie P. Bragg Funeral Homes, Inc. (Folder 146)
      - I.L.G.W.U. (International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union) sponge. (Folder 147)
      - I.L.G.W.U. (International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union) button. (Folder 148)
      - I.L.G.W.U. scarf (Folder 149)
        Polyester scarf, 32" x 32", with International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union logo. Donated to the Working in Paterson Project by I.L.G.W.U. member and retired garment worker Florence DiStefano of Paterson, N.J. 1994.
      - Textile Sample 1 (Folder 150)
        Sample from Joseph Teshon, Inc. Color: Apricot.
      - Textile Sample 2 (Folder 151)
        Sample from Joseph Teshon, Inc. Color: Shell #242.
      - Textile Sample 3 (Folder 152)
        Sample from Joseph Teshon, Inc. Color: Rust and Yellow.
      - Textile Sample 4 (Folder 153)
        Sample form Joseph Teshon, Inc. Color: White and Blue.
      - Photograph (Folder 154)
        1 photograph of Great Falls in Peterson, New Jersey. March 14, 1936.
      - Traveling Small Distances (Folder 155)
        A booklet of poetry by June Avignone. Photographs by Ellen Denuto. 1993. Printed by Paterson Museum.
      - Street map of Paterson, Cliffton, and Passaic, New Jersey (Folder 156)
        Published by Hagstrom. No date.